so what I'd like to teach is class seven
which is about them so you have to turn
and give them the right homework Tim
okay and this is called the nine states
of meditation okay in in your meditation
career the evolution of your meditation
will go through nine steps nine very
typical steps okay
and it's easier you know I don't know
when I was a kid I lived in Arizona and
the roads here are long hundreds of
miles and we used to go to San Diego for
go surfing it's a eight hours drive okay
Los Angeles is like 11 hours and we
would go with my mom and dad four boys
locked in a car and we used to fight
constantly the whole way we are fighting
you know and we keep asking our mom and
dad
what are we almost there
and they said almost there like only
seven hours and 45 minutes
we went 15 minutes you know and the kids
keep asking are we almost there you know
and later we learned how to read the
sign san diego 365 miles san diego 364
miles we learned how to read the signs
okay in meditation it's very helpful if
someone tells you how to know how far
you you win how far you have to go okay
these are the highway signs for
meditation there are nine highway signs
I'm gonna teach you tonight these are
very traditional they come from
Kamala Sheila's famous book on
meditation stages of meditation Bhavana
Kalama
okay
and there are nine basic stages then
it's very helpful because why I'd like
to teach business it's very easy to
measure okay how many dollars did you do
how many thought demands did you sell
there's a number then you know how far
you went right but with inner progress
how much is your compassion how many
miles of compassion you know well are
you like 99% compared from 43% how far
did you reach you see how patient are
you
you know when the yoga teacher is
killing you in India how patient can you
be okay what's your number forty three
percent fifty three percent how patient
are you it's very difficult to put a
number on the inner inner progress
progress of your heart but in meditation
we are lucky because they gave us nine
highway signs how far you win then you
can judge how far you went okay you can
guess how far you went okay here we go
number one say sim joke Bock sim japa
okay so your teacher is teaching you
tongue man meditation for example okay
and the teacher said choose another
person you know who is sick or they're
unhappy or they're having some problems
with their husband wife something okay
choose somebody okay and think about
them okay and then you choose somebody
in your mind you know maybe you have a
friend who's lonely or something and and
for a few seconds you put your mind on
them that's level one okay for a few
seconds you put your mind on them then
immediately you start thinking about
what's for lunch
what time is get scarce I gonna stop
early tonight also you know you start
thinking about other things
so just you kiss the meditation object
for one second hi bye quick kiss that
you gave to your wife on the way to your
job you're not gonna do this oh it's
very
that's called stems oppa just put the
mind on the RJ and then start getting
distracted okay but its progress and the
very important factor during that level
one of how many levels nine levels is
that you have listened to your teacher
you got instructions from your teacher
level one assumes that you went to a
class and the teacher gave you a
meditation object okay they said think
about someone you know who's having
trouble okay it's having trouble in
their life okay so we often say that
level one is reached by just going to
the teacher asking for what to meditate
about okay so that's already a lot of
progress that's already a lot of
progress and it's very brief periods of
time if you compare the time that you
are thinking about the person with the
problem and the time you are thinking
about what's for lunch it's about 10%
and 90% which one is the lunch 90%
that's okay you can call it 10% and it's
not bad it's a start it's a start
okay it's a start don't don't it's not
useless you know
it's very rare to meet a good meditation
teacher it's very difficult to meet a
good meditation teacher okay so if you
reach level 1 you are already one person
out of a million okay
you're already a very special person
okay so don't think you are bad
meditator if you're 10% meditator you
are better than 1 million people really
okay at least you started meditating
okay people who cannot meditate people
who never meet a good meditation teacher
are like people who never learned to
read it's very similar it's very very
similar okay if you don't have the good
karma to meet a really good meditation
teacher it's almost like you never
learned how to read and you will go
through your whole life surrounded by
all you know you pick up this thing and
you look at this thing inside and you
have no no idea what it says you're kind
of blind it's a kind of blindness okay
you have eyes but it's all just squiggle
squiggle you know you have no idea what
it says okay so imagine if your mom and
your dad those kind teachers never sent
you to school you know they never taught
you to read and you can't read people
who can't meditate people who never meet
a meditation teacher they are very very
similar to people who can't read books
okay
they are blind it's a kind of blindness
okay so if you reach level 1 10% on the
object 90 percent on the hamburger
veggie burger you are very lucky you are
very special okay you're cool eh are
cool say jump arm
all right okay you're okay you're lucky
all right level - say again - japa again
- japa okay you are able to stay on the
meditation object what's the meditation
on doing your friend who's having
trouble yeah your friend who's having
trouble
okay you have a rosary right and you go
slow okay
start at the mother bead here tradition
to use your third finger of your left
hand okay you have to practice it hurts
for a couple days don't don't use your
usual hand right hand and use your thumb
okay that's a lazy
okay there's special prana here that's I
think that's why they use a wedding ring
so it practice using your left hand and
put the Rosary on top of the third and
fourth fingers right and then count like
done okay Oh money pay me how loud
geshe-la they say if there's a spirit in
the room they should be able to hear you
because there's always a spirit in the
room a couple of spirits in the room so
so don't go then they're like what no
you can help the spirits it's a
tradition they say there are many
protests everywhere every room has
spread there are many preachers in this
land this land was a war zone many
Native people died here and those
spirits are still here so help them out
you don't have to go all mad a baby who
and they they all have hearing aids okay
you can just see how many just a normal
quiet okay like that but it's
traditional to say it loud enough for a
spirit who's sitting next to you okay
they don't have to say what
now if you can hold your mind on that
person for as long as it takes to do 108
beats right then you reached level 2
okay you not like this I'm gonna find my
own money baby alright just normal you
can check how long it is I don't know
one minute two minutes it's about one
minute if you can hold your mind on that
person without thinking about lunch now
for boys that's almost impossible for
girls I think it's easier boys thing
about lunch every breath it's a breath
practice okay
okay but you can check okay you can
check okay and I mean it takes many
years to learn to watch your mind it
takes many years of practice to notice
when your mind is not on the object okay
it's very definitely difficult to use
the mind to check them okay the mine
which is sleepy has trouble to check the
mind which is sleepy you seen I mean so
it's very difficult it takes a lot of
practice to catch yourself when you
start to think about veggie burger okay
it's difficult it takes some time okay
but try try my teacher when we did the
ten breaths he said if you think about
something else start at one start again
at one so I'm like what's for breakfast
what's perfect one two what's for
breakfast one what one then he say okay
stop stop it's like half an hour I
didn't reach to okay
how honest are you about yourself don't
cheat who are you cheating
you just nobody else okay you cheating
yourself oh I thought about a Hamburg
but but not too much
okay one two three so don't cheat by the
way when they say take ten breaths
before the meditation try for five
minutes
if you reach three you are very lucky
okay if you reach more than three you're
not being honest seriously from many
years of practice when I do the four
powers in my meditation because I'm
jealous of the other teachers I usually
break it again during the four powers
you understand I'm confessing then I'm
jealous and then I start to feel jealous
during the confession okay it's the same
with counting to ten okay so if you can
keep your mind on the object for that
long which is unusual by the way I would
say if you could keep your mind for one
whole rosary on the object this a sign
would be that you are the best business
person you know because you have focused
okay not okay it will show in your
normal life you see you will be the best
mother you will be the best business
person you will be the best yoga teacher
because you have focus okay so if you
want to know did you really reach level
two
I think a person who has reached level
two they are already one of the best
business people in their city or
something that's how much focus normal
people don't have more than two or three
breaths of focus nobody okay if you can
keep your mind on something for two
minutes
you can invent an iPhone okay most
people never get there most people in
their whole life they never get there
okay so don't think level two is stupid
level two is cool okay you're already
amazing business person
or amazing mother or amazing wife
husband okay
all right you cooked the best of anybody
no it's also focused right takes a lot
of focus to cook well right okay that's
why they call me pot burner my llama
said he didn't call me Michael he called
me pop burner because I always burned at
dinner okay that's not I was to cook for
eight years then he finally he finally
kicked me out of the kitchen okay if
your llama makes you cook burn
everything for eight years then they
kick you out then you can study okay by
the way during the free now how far are
you in the nine levels how far did you
go in the nine levels is judged by how
much sleepiness do you have and how much
busy mind you have okay two two enemies
of meditation busy mine and sleep in
mine all nine levels are judged by how
much busy mind you have and how much
sleep in mind you have okay here's sleep
in mine you ready it's actually more
dangerous because you think you're
meditating you didn't move you didn't
move for half an hour everything's quiet
[Music]
but actually you're just sleepy okay
many many people who meditate for too
long I really just sleeping that without
without snoring one day I hit my head
really hard on the wall I fell asleep
completely and I hit my head I got a big
bump my teachers are now you're a
meditator
[Laughter]
okay so during the first two levels what
percentage of your time is sleep in mind
a busy mind busy - thinking about what
you have to do after meditation okay
it's the big enemy of meditation when we
have to do list I finish this stupid
meditation I talk this life spent 10
minutes
oh it's 11 minutes I say it's last week
oh no it's 12 minutes two weeks ago then
you start thinking about all the things
you have to do today okay that's busy
mine sleeping - just you know be careful
cuz it feels like meditation okay how
what percent of your mind even when
you're thinking about the person in the
Tollman
what percent of your mind has busy mind
or sleep in mind in the first two levels
100% okay you you mind the we call
listen quality of your meditation okay
quality of your meditation yoga poses
are the same right you can do a yoga
pose really well with high quality yoga
pose and then you can do it really
sloppy okay everything's a little bit
cooking and your breath is bad and
you're thinking about lunch okay high
quality meditation in the first two
levels almost zero okay almost zero you
can say that maybe you can remember to
think about the person but the quality
of the meditation is definitely
economy-class
okay definitely small Volkswagen okay
cheap car I'm not very good and that's
okay that's okay you don't get better
meditation takes time yoga and
meditation they take time to make
progress it doesn't come fast
everyone thinks when they start yoga
they're gonna be able to do
yoga teacher does it takes years it
takes years your body opens very slow
your mind opens floor but you just keep
trying keep trying okay okay so that's
number two Gunda japa in tibetan means a
little bit of a flow little bit of a
flow you is the time it takes to do a
rosary how much is it 1 minute 2 minutes
90 seconds okay Penza how fast you stay
right normal okay good well it depends
on how long the mantra okay anyway we're
talking on many people okay I'm taking
home anything thank you
don't worry okay in level 3 but okay how
much busy mind how much sleep in mind in
number 1 level 2 almost the whole thing
even when you're thinking about the
person half of your mind is thinking
about lunch okay okay say Linda japa
lenta japa this is interesting okay this
and I didn't understand it it took me a
couple years to understand it then
lembeh in tibetan means a patch on your
clothes
so usually jeans they open here right
and if you know a good tailor they can
keep it going for another six months or
something they patch it from the inside
they put a patch on the on the hole okay
so how should we say I used to
misunderstand this because I thought the
meditation goes and goes and goes and
then there's a patch when you're off the
object okay and then you fix it and then
you come back on the object but some
people say the patch is the time on the
object
you wear the pants for two years then
you put a patch on it and some people
say that two years is off the object so
it means short periods on the object
okay some people say okay like then so
most of the scriptures say when you
reach level three you can do maybe ten
minutes of meditation and then you lose
it for two minutes and then you come
back and you do ten minutes okay okay so
it's more time on the object then off
the empty okay more time on the object
then off the object so that's what patch
means a patch means you're gonna lose
the object for a while all right
the patch patch sounds like you're
putting something but in this case it
means something's not there got it the
meditation is not there's a gap a short
gap when you're not on the object okay
that's called path okay then you have to
repass then you come back for ten
minutes and then you lose it again for
two minutes then you come back for ten
minutes okay so the sign of level three
is more time on the object then compared
to off the object okay which means level
one and two is more time okay and
there's a very famous teaching on
meditation that says pub Uncas says I
can't describe everything to you in
words you have to taste it you have to
try it I can give you some guidelines I
can tell you a lot about meditation but
the real meditation teaching has to take
place in your own experience there are
things about meditation that no one can
teach you just time on the cushion
beagle on the cushion ok and then you
will learn I can't teach you everything
about meditation you have to teach
yourself a lot of because each person
has a different experience ok so I can
describe
things roughly but from the words you
cannot get the full meaning okay you
have to try it yourself okay that's a
very famous meditation instruction okay
cool okay let's go to double four okay
that's called neo japa seigneur japa
they call it how should I call it
mm-hmm you are constant on the object
with lousy quality okay got it
you are constant on the object you can
hold the object ten minutes twenty
minutes you can hold the object but the
quality of the attention is not very
good there is still a lot of sleepiness
and there's still a lot of thinking
about other things but you don't lose
the object okay it gets fuzzy it gets
grey it's like heavy rain when you're
driving okay like you can't see through
the glass very clearly but you can see
you can see the lights of the car in
front of you but it's not clear okay the
quality is not good but you don't lose
the lights in front of you
okay you are driving and it's a heavy
rain and you can see the lights in front
of you but it's not clear okay got it
so that's level four you don't lose the
object okay you stay on the object but
not very strong some scriptures say
holding a rosary poorly and it it can
drop easy you know you're like okay
level four you don't lose it but you're
close you're like okay got it
you don't you don't just you don't drop
that rosary about your club you know you
keep stupid and slipping okay like that
okay and the quality is not very good
that's it difficult it's like like you
have a telescope and the things not in
focus okay so you can see something is
there but it's not in focus okay got it
the focus is not very good that's a D
okay so why is the quality lousy you
still have some busy mind and you still
have some sleep in mind but it's not so
serious that you drop the object okay
it's not so serious that you drop the
object so level four is actually pretty
cool that means you're pretty you almost
you're a better meditator than a hundred
other men Athenians okay if you can get
to level four in this lifetime you're a
champ um okay you're a cool person but
we want to reach level nine of course
okay
Saito Chiba it's called level five is
called controlling your mind you have
control you are the boss of your own
mind okay you are the boss of your own
mind and you have a thing called you
have a tool called shishun satiation
okay Shane is a little guy that you hire
to sit in the back of your head that's
what happened to me in John
it's a little guy he sits here in the
back and he watches to mind and if he
sees a problem he pushes the smoke alarm
beep beep beep beep okay it's called
shishun it's a meditation tool that you
have to develop okay I don't know like
in yoga you learn to watch your breath
or your balance or something like that
but when you meditate you develop a
smoke alarm in the mind okay and it
watches the rest of the mind and if
there's if the mind starts thinking
about hamburgers then it goes beep EEP
EEP EEP EEP okay or you start to get
sleepy then it it goes beep beep beep
okay so by level-5 you have good session
you see a shin muscle it's strong good
the smoke alarm what's the smoke sleepy
or thinking about other things sleepy so
you develop a special muscle in your
mind that says you are not you are gonna
lose the object if you keep going okay
okay you're gonna lose be careful I can
see you're getting sleepy wake up okay
by the way question $20 does Jason say
wake up Oh too many $200 let's cancel it
that's tempeh okay say Sheen and timber
okay smoke alarm and lasso you know
lasso
there's a lot of Cowboys around here
they actually wear guns in this town
they walk in with guns you know they
have these guns I was in the ice there
used to be ice cream place and I took my
Israeli friend there and these guys are
walking with guns you know and he's he's
a giver of they making a movie
I said no this is not a movie this is
real they have a real gun keep your
mouth shut then they have a special rope
right and they can catch the cow and
pull it in timba means to throw the rope
on the cow's head and pull the cup
what's the cow your attention your
attention okay so there's two mental
functions you have to develop for
meditation very famous Association
timber Shan timber chasing you can call
smoke alarm chamber you can call Cowboys
rope okay and then you bring them mind
bang okay the mind starts to think about
hamburger you say wow then the Cowboys
like where where is he where is he
over there he start to think about
hamburger okay I got him come back
coming you need both okay you need smoke
alarm and cowboy cowboy rope okay that's
number five
so you're shaking at level five is very
strong okay shaking at level five is
very strong and you already stopped okay
sleepy mind has two kinds of sleep in
mind just two kinds of sleepy mind okay
one is where geshe-la hit his head on
the wall and got a bump okay we call
obvious sleepy mind you can try it if
you if you didn't fall asleep in
meditation it means you don't meditate
because it happens to everybody
[Music]
so that we call obvious dumbest obvious
sleeping mine okay
at level five you defeated it you don't
it's not possible anymore to fall asleep
completely in the meditation it's not
possible okay but there's a subtle sleep
in mine shuttles I'll show you subtle
sleep in mine you ready here we go
it looks good right
but actually you spaced out you're not
thinking about this person who has a
problem right you just look good okay
so subtle sleep in mind is very
dangerous very very dangerous it feels
like meditation and I guess 90% of
people who meditate who don't have this
training are doing subtle sleep in mind
much of the time and they don't know
okay so be careful this this is the
danger guy he's a big danger falling
asleep hitting your head on the wall
there's evidence there's a bomb
okay subtle sleepiness you can do it for
many years and you don't know you're
doing it okay if you meditate too long
more than ten minutes in the beginning I
will say it's a guarantee you have
subtle Thomas okay guarantee those
people who meditate meditate for two
hours forget it okay not possible not
possible I know and I'm meditating for
50 years okay not possible okay if you
can do an hour it's enough okay without
getting sleepy alright do you still have
the object on fifth level yeah you are
still an object that's why it's so
dangerous
did you still think about the sick
person yes was the quality of the
meditation high quality business class
meditation no it was economy class it
was sleepy
it was sleeping okay got it
okay you keep at you have to keep asking
what's the quality of the meditation
what's the quality of the focus what's
the quality of the attention okay
how good is it you can do a yoga pose
over and over and over for years and
it's not correct and it's sloppy okay
and then you can do a yoga pose with
great care great attention great
training and it's completely different
right cool
that's level five do you have obvious
sleep in mind no do you have dangerous
sleep in mind yes never fine okay now
that and that level is called
controlling the mind each level has its
own name I'm gonna tell you the names
again you can check your notes okay
level one is called putting your mind on
the ante putting your mind on the object
just briefly like kissing your wife
goodbye in the kitchen okay not before
you go to China or something that's
longer okay
number two some continuity some like
let's call it how about we call it one
rosary okay let's call level two one
with me that's double to put that long
you can call the object okay number
three patches off the object patches off
the object short patches off the object
mostly on the object but patches off the
on thing okay cool that's level three
okay level four how are we gonna comment
glued to the object but bad glue cheap
glue cheap glue
let's call cheap glue level four is
called cheap blue your mind is stuck to
the object but that glue is not very
good you might lose it okay cheap glue
is number four please write commercial
telling me changed anything okay let him
know maybe we get in trouble okay number
five what are we gonna call it you have
you you are in control of the mind you
are in control not very good control
just you don't have obviously P mind
okay
at least you have this much control you
can tell they're mine no more no more
sleeping okay
can I space out yes that's next level
can I sleep no can I space out yes got
it
space out like okay but not asleep okay
got it
okay level weary six ABCD yeah okay six
that one every Chinese person agrees I
start using this from my friends in
America they're like what are you doing
I'm like sits there like what are you
doing you got some on your finger
it's called okay the Tibetan were in a
shoe a Champa it means peace peace
peaceful
it means peaceful peaceful mind yeah she
were cheaper peaceful
the session is extremely strong the
smoke alarm is extremely sensitive
someone comes in smoking a cigarette
it's gonna go on your husband gets angry
and the little smoke comes out of his
ear it's gonna go on that nobody guy
thinking little smoke
it's gonna go up the decision is very
powerful at level what are we on say
yeah six the watchfulness is variation
is very powerful okay and now you gotta
understand something and we said it many
times at DCI these are students they
know all this when you drive a car okay
when you're driving a car a new person
they just hold it like this you know and
they're like this and then the car
starts to go a little bit cooking and
they just they're like this okay and
then when you get more comfortable
driving a car you learn to go like this
small corrections right and the way it
goes is when the car starts going to
left you correct to the right okay and
then the car starts going to the right
and you correct Allah and after one year
of driving it's automatic you don't
think about it you know you can talk to
your friend you can listen to rock and
roll
and your hands are like this and you
don't even notice it okay but the
tendency of driving is that if you just
hold it like this it will start to go
off to the side okay then you have to
correct but the nature of correction is
to over correct
that's human being you go too far to the
left and you know oh my god and you go
like this and you go too far to the
right you say oh my god Nina go there
and then you go there and that's why a
drivers here watch it drivers hands now
and they never stop it
bad driver doesn't move but a good
drivers like okay
their hand is always moving and they
don't think about it okay
meditation is the same why am I talking
about that in meditation we have to
correct the meditation you're getting
sleepy you're getting sleepy okay well
what are you supposed to do about sleepy
we're gonna talk about it when we do the
russian-speaking program okay there's a
way to turn the car back but usually you
go too far then you have to try to get
more sleepy okay so you have to keep
correcting the mind in meditation and
you have to learn how to do it okay
so at level 6 you are now detecting
subtle busy mind
subtle busy mind what's the word in
Tibetan for zero dollars you know Ching
what um oh please human computer I got
you but what's the colloquial expression
come I should have bet money it's called
water under the ice
okay when the stream gets frozen and you
can walk on the ice but underneath
there's still the water is flowing
pretty fast okay top the top is not
moving the top is frozen but underneath
the water is moving fast okay and that's
called subtle busy mind what it means is
you are still thinking about what you
have to do today but sub level sub level
you are holding it dumb the mind is
still saying three crack we've got a
meaning for crack we're gonna mean Oh
finally I got some I said do today but
its core it's under the water it's under
the ice
you see your mind is not talking but
it's ready to break out
okay it's a water under the ice on a
spring day which is getting warmer and
it's ready to break out okay the busy
mine is ready to break out didn't really
stop
no you just suppress it you just
suppress it you see and it's still
flowing under the mine okay it's like if
someone dies that you love for years
it's flowing under the mine okay for
years
and it will it will break out you know a
couple of times a day you will think
about them right and it will break out
sub that grief that pain it didn't go
away it's just covered and then it's
gonna break out we call subtle busy my
son a busy man you are so busy you have
so many things to do today that even if
your meditation is strong level six
still the schedule is on your mind
things are on your mind or you had a big
fight with your husband three days ago
that it's still under your mind and it's
gonna break out okay got it
we call subtle busy mind it could be a
worry
it could be someone a sink that you love
it could be I don't know someone died
that you love it could be anything
you're losing your job that the worry is
just under the ice okay that's called
subtle busy mine
what is subtle dull mine you just spaced
out in English because spaced out you
know you know there's no quality to the
attention there's no quality to the
attention okay got it
alright that's level six okay
and by level six there's not much danger
of subtle slipping mine by level six
you have peace put to peace sleep in
mind there's no sleep in mine obviously
and saddle sleeping mine both gone okay
by level six the only thing you have to
worry about is the your daily schedule
break here today shut up okay but it's
still flowing under in your mind okay
okay in the subconscious mind got it
so by level six what's gone I'll sleep
in mind even little sleep in mind you
are like look you are like good
attention good attention but maybe
today's schedule is pressing on your
mind
maybe today schedules pushing wait shut
up okay okay got it
no no sleep in mine but maybe today's
schedule is gonna push up okay all right
level seven it's called total peace
total peace okay guess what happened at
level seven
yeah no more busy mind any kind of busy
mind I guess let's check yeah yeah it's
just no big danger of subtle sleeping
mind or subtle busy mind okay no big
danger what's that mean maybe there's a
some small danger and only at level 7
the Camila Sheila says your smoke alarm
and your cowboy rope are perfect strong
smoke alarm strong cowboy rope if
something goes wrong in the mind
immediately you're gonna get B P P P
okay and immediately you can pull the
mind back okay the word timber also
means to remember so many people
mistranslated as the recollection which
is not okay it means pull the mind back
to the object okay it's a cowboy rope
okay we gotta change all the
- cowboy rope just kidding okay how many
we got to go Tim I'm gonna make it okay
level ain't never aim we call single
point in mind a Kagura a single point
what single point mean you have a sharp
mind like a pencil right no yeah one
object so when I say single point you
think a laser you know it doesn't mean
that it means you can keep the mind on
one object and you don't move okay
total single point okay no don't know
sleep in mine and no busy mind at all
okay at this point that level in the
conversation is how often do you have to
correct how often do you have to make
adjustments how often do you have to
make adjustments okay by level eight the
only question is how often during the
meditation session do you have to make
an adjustment in your mind and the
answer is once when you start when you
start the meditation you have to tweak
you have to make small adjustments oh
I'm a little sleepy beep I'm a little
busy mind people so in the first few
minutes you finish all the adjustments
then you're flowing then you're flowing
but in the very beginning you're like
you need a little more sleep turn this
down okay everything's about and then
it's like and tell you finish smooth
ride straight line okay
after the initial adjustments okay got
it
[Music]
so what's level nine
no little watch time to meditate okay
okay then no adjustment time no small oh
I got a you know it's it's very
beautiful maybe it will happen to you
once a year you just sit down and you're
okay and it's it's beautiful if it takes
a long time don't worry if you but there
will come a time like if you have to
translate a book or you have to catch
your anger you're starting to get upset
and you just go and then finished okay
that's real meditation okay
the name of that is no joke no joke
means deep meditation okay and that's
the one you need for see emptiness okay
that's the one so it's a long journey
and it's not gonna happen in one day or
one week or one month okay
there's all these romantic stories about
the young monk who went out to chop wood
and sorry I'm penis it's not true okay
it takes a lot of work and it takes and
it takes years okay and just start okay
it's like yoga I don't worry about my
yoga I just come every day
I don't worry I can do this I can't do
that I don't think about it I just come
every day that's all then I let the
teacher beat me up and right and I'm
better okay just come every day got it
by the way the nine levels are in those
paths especially the the turning of the
path okay we'll talk about it okay we'll
talk about someday we should just do the
poster that would be really sweet
teaching maybe I'll try this week just
do the poster I don't know let's see
it'd be nice to give a teaching on the
whole poster I've never
I think I've done it once maybe we do
that for fun
Tim won't like it because we won't
finish the homework there'll be a lot of
fun let's do that okay let's let's blow
up the teacher training if we have time
okay if we have time if we have time
I'll do it I like to upset him bad boy
okay that's anything tonight yeah that's
it one minute left
any CSP guys have a mandala Stanley can
you suggest somebody okay listen if you
want to look good just say the first two
words loud sorry
and then don't worry about the rest
that's what we do in the monastery when
we are young we go
it's called wah wah we has a word it's
koala sorry
just get the first two words right okay
there they are
okay very loud on the first two words
then while forgive her she met long time
near arancini and a game buddy sang
Gatien to maintain who are you the
drunken dashing me son I'm you shake
total she said I'm your share
Kuniko okay cool thanks for being good
students in my house I try not to have
chairs with arms right ooh have chairs
with no arms and then I practice my half
Lotus during dinner or when I'm typing I
do five minutes with this leg and then I
do five minutes with this thing and then
you can do you can learn a full Lotus
you know in a few months if you if you
do that way you know cut all the arms
off your chairs and then just have one
leg up when you're working okay and get
a habit like that on a plane you have to
have business class really okay that's
one of the reasons